<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="https://pancakedstudios.github.io/index.css" media="screen"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <generator>RSS Builder by B!Soft</generator>
    <title>Pancaked Studios</title>
    <link>https://pancakedstudios.github.io</link>
    <description>for chao eyes only. alot of the posts are outdated but they are here for archival purposes</description>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <copyright>Pancaked Studios</copyright>
    <item>
      <title>The Return of the Devlog</title>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 11:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <link>https://paper.wf/pancakedstudios/well-its-been-a-while-since-the-last-post-hasnt-it</link>
      <description><![CDATA[Well, it's been a while since the last post, hasn't it? Wait, let me check... 171 days? 5 ½ months? Huh.

Okay, let me get this shit out of the way. A lot of shit was added since that blog post.

Here is a very short rundown of what the hell we added since then:

- Texture pages now load externally and when they actually need to, if the game needs to load a lot of sprites then we don't have to immediately load every single one, all at once
- The first half of The Centre Caves! That's the first level of the game by the way. We just need to make the second half
- An actually reliable and not messy input system, courtesy of JuJuAdams' Input extension. Check him out, please
- An enemy framework. We called the test enemy Carl. Because of course we did
- Scrapped that boring, shitty looking test tutorial in favour of a better looking one. Or maybe not. It's up to personal preference, but we're going with the better looking one
- Discord rich presence support. Discord sucks but eh, it's cool. Until YoYoGames sent out a patch to GMS2 breaking the extension we used for it. Fucking god damn it
- And many, many more

Here are some highlights that the game was involved with:

- The game was at SAGE 2022! It was a great event, and we might be there next year. Hopefully once the game comes out (mid-late 2023) the game can be there. 
  To play the demo, just search SFGHQ “chao adventure”, or go to the SAGE website and scroll down in the games tab until you find it. It's in the top section of the “Fan Games” part of the page.
- We started the private alpha for the game back in July. It's still going on but we'll start the private beta once the second half of The Centre Caves is finished.

Go play the demo here: https://sonicfangameshq.com/forums/showcase/chao-adventure.1253/

See you later, or probably in at least 100 days. Maybe.
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Switching to GameMaker</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 04:30:11 -0500</pubDate>
      <link>https://pancakedstudios.wordpress.com/2022/04/28/switching-to-gamemaker/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[So, literally right fucking after our previous devblog post, we actually switched to GameMaker Studio 2 for Chao Adventure. 
And it’s going 10x more smoothly this time instead of us programming the game directly from the ground up. 

<img src="https://pancakedstudios.files.wordpress.com/2022/04/image-1.png"> 
Also, we’ve been active on Sonic Fangames HQ recently, and we even made a thread for the game, which you can find <a href="https://sonicfangameshq.com/forums/threads/chao-adventure-not-the-vmu-game.783">here</a>. 
It definitely will be at SAGE 2022, and we hope to see you there.

SIDENOTE: We are planning to upload the game to rpgmaker.net once the game is finished, as well as itch.io and the SFGHQ Showcase, which is also where the SAGE 2022 demo of the game will be.

See you next time, and at SAGE 2022 in September!]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The April Devblog</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 03:22:37 -0500</pubDate>
      <link>https://pancakedstudios.wordpress.com/2022/04/23/the-april-devblog/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[April is almost over. So WHY NOT MAKE A DEVBLOG POST, RIGHT????

<img src="https://pancakedstudios.files.wordpress.com/2022/04/image.png?w=1024">

Wait, why? I’ll explain.

Basically programming the collision engine is a fucking hell and it’s going terribly. 
Personally, I’m working on the art of Chao Adventure and not doing much programming,
although I do contribute some programming from time to time, such as the window resolution being bigger and making most of the player code, 
which in my opinion is a mess.

For now, collisions are the main thing Memosek (the programmer) is going to work on in terms of the game.

Well, this was short. See you later.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to April.</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 2 Apr 2022 01:01:53 -0500</pubDate>
      <link>https://pancakedstudios.wordpress.com/2022/04/02/welcome-to-april/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[I don’t have much to say, but Chao Adventure will have a seperate website from our website. (It’s still our game though.)

Sorry for the short announcement, and I’m also taking a break from Discord.

>wow this did not last<]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome Aboard... (this stupid newsletter.)</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 09:59:11 -0500</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<Hey, this is still really old and outdated. This is just an archive from Substack.>

Welcome to the Pancaked Studios newsletter!
This is the new newsletter.

Previously, all Pancaked Studios-related things such as Chao Adventure had their updates on Niko’s actual newsletter.

Now, we’re going to use this instead! Although, not much will change.
Quick Recap: What the hell is Chao Adventure?

Chao Adventure is our XNA puzzle-platformer Sonic fangame. You play as Azure, who is a Chao. Yup, that’s the recap. we told you it was going to be quick!
When is it coming out?

No release date for the full game. But a demo for SAGE 2022 will release during that, so you can have a “first slice” of the game.
Okay, what is here for today?

On Niko’s newsletter posts, he stated that the story was mostly done. This was true. We had set up an entire Discord channel where we would chronologically plan out the story (no dialog) and some events in the game. 
We finished doing that in about 2 hours or so that lasted from midnight of February 12 (channel creation) to early morning of February 13. (the actual story being planned out)

At this point, we decided the game would basically be “insincere” satire against the Changed community and the game itself. You could really consider the game a high quality shitpost.

Memosek (a team member) is currently working on programming the collision system for the game. Caden (another team member) messed around with making some sound effects and finding some on freesound.org, while Niko was doing graphics. Both Caden and Niko were doing the story, alongside a friend of the two named Bruhlads.
What has happened today, specifically?

Niko migrated the program used to make the ingame art from Aseprite to Paint.NET. While this seems like a downgrade, he mainly done it so that team members could add artwork to a huge sheet before having the artwork being added to the XNA content pipeline. Aseprite is a paid program that can be compiled for free, but he did not want members being required to use a compiled version instead of an older version.

Niko also now has Adobe Flash CS4 to make promotional art, due to Flash being a vector program and is easier for him to draw with a WACOM tablet when doing art that isn’t pixel-based.
Niko’s plans for what happens after Memosek finishes programming collisions

Niko’s plans are mainly these:

    Revamp how movement works for the player so that input code doesn’t look really stupid

    Replace old tiles with new ones that would actually be used ingame

    Have the gun and bullet system fixed

    Make the NPC system

    Make player starting location be specified by the map instead of directly in the player code

Non-Chao Adventure related things

Niko tried out Opera GX for a bit. It ran fine for a few days but then became laggy on his laptop.

Caden is probably going to de-bloat and de-spook his Windows installation.

Niko’s going to try being active on Discord servers more.

That’s all!

(P.S: Niko wrote this. I actually wrote this in third person.)]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Chao Adventure story is &lt;not&gt; done!</title>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 09:55:46 -0500</pubDate>
      <link>https://nikostormkilla.substack.com/p/the-chao-adventure-story-is-done</link>
      <description><![CDATA[<Update on this: The story is not done. It needs to have the game ready to actually start making it. This was really old, but enjoy the archive.>

Now, BEFORE you get your hopes up, NO. The game is not done.

But the story of the game is mostly complete, so that makes it alot easier to actually make this game. Actually, not really, but that's one less weight off our shoulders.

The game currently needs ALOT of programming to be done and also needs alot of fixes, such as the fact that you can cause a stack overflow exception when you initiate the gun services. Yes, that can happen and it needs to be fixed.

But hey, we're a bit closer to getting this game done.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chao Adventure: THE ANNOUNCEMENT</title>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 09:53:19 -0500</pubDate>
      <link>https://nikostormkilla.substack.com/p/chao-adventure-the-announcement</link>
      <description><![CDATA[Coming Soon™ at SAGE 2022, which is also Coming Soon™

No pictures will be shown here. We have only started development a month ago. “But what is Chao Adventure, even though we can’t see what it looks like at the moment?”

Chao Adventure is a Sonic and Fez fangame starring Chao from the Sonic Adventure games. Currently being developed with the XNA Framework in C#. (Not Monogame or FNA, we will use those for porting) 
It is a puzzle platformer where you play as a Chao, armed with a gun, and instead of using it for actual combat, 
it is used for solving projectile-based puzzles and sometimes knocking down certain objects to be used for object/entity-based puzzles.

As I mentioned above, we will not show any pictures at the moment. But you’ll see what it looks like at SAGE 2022. It’s Coming Soon™ in the spring.

I hope I can give you more updates!

>wow, this is really outdated<]]></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>